[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我犯过一次错误，我需要承认。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I made a bug once and I need to confess.
我需要坦白和你分享这件事。
I need to come clean and share this with you.
那是在2001年。
It was in 2001.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我用Java写的，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And I was writing in Java,
我编写了第一批JSON解析器之一，它是引用的一部分
I wrote one of the first JSON parsers and it was part of a reference
实现，向人们展示编写JSON解析器是多么容易。
implementation to show people how easy it was to write a JSON parser.
它包含了这个语句，它创建了一个索引变量，
And it included this statement, which created an index variable,
其将字符计数到正在被解析的字符串或流中。
which counted characters into the string or a stream that was being parsed.
所以如果存在语法错误，
So if there were a syntax error,
我们可以告诉您错误发生在什么字符位置。
we could tell you at what character position that error occurred.
一个int足够大到可以覆盖大约20亿个字符，
And an int is big enough to cover what about 2 billion characters,
这是相当大的。
which is pretty big.
也就是2千兆字节在当时是一个大的磁盘驱动器
That was 2 gigabytes was a big disk drive at that time and
我使用Chase的方式，他们从来没有得到过这样的信息
the way I was using chase and they never had a message that
比几个K还大，所以我认为这是一个很大的空间。
was bigger than a couple of K, so I thought that's a lot of headroom.
你太慷慨了。
That's being pretty generous.
我是未来的证据，这很好。
I'm future proof, this is good.
所以几年前，我从某人那里得到了一份错误报告
So a couple years ago, I got a bug report from somebody
他向解析器传递了一个JSON文本，该解析器有几个
who had passed a JSON text to the parser that was several
大小为千兆字节，包含超过2千兆字节的语法错误。
gigabytes in size that contained a syntax error past 2 gigabytes.
我的解析器提供的错误消息是严重错误的
And the error message that my parser provided was wildly wrong and
他们看了代码
they looked at the code and
他们很快就发现了为什么它是严重错误的，因为我说了，int。
they very quickly figured out why it was wildly wrong, and was because I said, int.
所以我讨厌int。
So I hate int.
INT很糟糕
Int's terrible.
INT，我认为这是编程历史上最糟糕的想法之一
Int, I think is one of the worst ideas in the history of programming and
我讨厌int的原因是因为它在溢出时所做的事情。
the reason I hate int is because what it does on overflow.
所以，让我们从哲学的角度来谈一谈。
So, let's talk philosophically.
那么，如果您有一个太大的值而不能放入一个内存单元，那么应该发生什么呢？
So, what should happen if you have a value that's too big to fit in a cell of memory?
应该发生什么？
What should happen?
有一个流派的思想说，嗯，CPU应该拖曳它。
There's one school of thought that says, well, the CPU should haul it.
有点老派了。
That's kind of old school.
你不会那样得到99分的，但是
You're not going get 99s that way, but
至少你可以保证你不会造成任何糟糕的结果。
at least you're guaranteed you're not going to create any bad results.
在混乱之前死亡。
Death before confusion.
有另一所学校说，我们会有一个中断。
There's another school that says, we'll have an interrupt.
我们将提出一个例外。
We'll raise an exception.
我们会走另一条路，这说明了一些事情。
We'll go to some other path, which says something.
[声音]做一些这方面的工作，给出一些警告和
[SOUND] Do some about that, give some warning and
防止原始操作失败。
prevent the original operation from falling through.
这很合理。
That's reasonable.
另一种方法会说，我们将提供一些哨兵，
Another approach would say, we'll provide some sentinel,
一些非值并将其放入内存中。
some non-value and put that in memory instead.
所以当你回去找它的时候，它会说，不知道你在找什么，
So when you go back and look for it, it'll say, don't know what you're looking for,
但它不在这里。
but it's not here.
另一种方法可能会说，取最大的适合的东西
Another approach might say, take the largest thing that does fit and
把那个放进去。
put that in there instead.
这叫做饱和。
It's called saturation.
在计算机图形和信号处理中这是一件合理的事情，
That's a reasonable thing to do in computer graphics and signal processing,
但你不会想在金融应用程序中这么做的。
but you don't wanna do that in financial applications.
不，不。
No, no, no.
但是假设你想要做的是最大化效果的可能性
But suppose what you want to do is maximize the likelihood in effect of
错误，我认为你要做的是丢弃最重要的部分
errors, I think what you wanna do is throw away the most significant bits and
不要告诉任何人，这就是我们所做的，我认为这是没有意义的。
don't tell anybody and that's what we do and I don't think it makes sense.
那么，我们为什么要这样做呢？
So, why do we do that?
这是因为它在50年代是有意义的。
It's because it made sense in the 50s.
所以在50年代，我们用真空管制造了计算机，真空管很大，
So in the 50s, we made computers out of vacuum tubes and vacuum tubes are big and
它们消耗大量的能量，变得很热，很快就会耗尽。
they consume a lot of power and they get hot and they burn out quickly.
所以你ALU里的管子越多，
So the more tubes you have in your ALU,
建造成本越高，运营成本越高，
the more it costs to build, the more it costs operate,
维护成本越高，平均失败时间越短。
the more it costs to maintain, the shorter the mean time to failure.
所以如果你能想出一种方法取出一些管子，这是一个巨大的胜利
So if you can figure out a way to take some tubes out, that's a huge win and
一些天才，我相信他是个天才。
some genius and I do believe he was a genius.
计算出如果我们使用补数运算而不是有符号幅值，
Figured out that if we use complement arithmetic instead of signed magnitude,
我们不需要实现减法电路。
we don't have to implement the subtract circuit.
我们要做的就是说句恭维话，
All we have to do is put a compliment,
其在ADD电路前面几乎是空闲的并且忽略溢出。
which is almost free in front of the add circuit and ignore the overflow.
太棒了。
That was brilliant.
这在当时是个好主意。
That was a great idea at the time.
但从那以后，摩尔定律随着数量的增加而变得疯狂
But since then, Moore's Law has gone crazy with the number of
芯片上可能存在的设备，我们没有重新考虑这一决定
devices that are possible on a chip and we have not reconsidered that decision that
是在50年代制造的，我认为我们已经远远超过了这一点。
was made in the 50s and I think we are way, way overdue on that.
更糟糕的是，内存曾经是极其稀缺和昂贵的。
To make this even worse, memory used to be extremely scarce and expensive.
机器中可能只有几个K。
Machine might only have a couple of K in it.
如果您还记得，Atari2600只有128字节的RAM。
The Atari 2600, if you remember, only had 128 bytes of RAM.
这是整个机器中的所有公羊。
That was all of the ram in the entire machine.
因此，您在为数字分配内存时非常小心。
So, you were really careful in allocating memory to numbers.
如果你能找到一种将两个数字转换成一个字节的方法，你就会这么做，
And if you could figure out a way to get two numbers into 1 byte, you would do it,
因为你没有太多
because you didn't have very many of them and
我们的编程语言仍然处于这种心态中。
our programming languages are still in that mindset.
例如，在Java中，有byte、char、short、in、long、float和
So for example, in Java, you've got byte, char, short, in, long, float and
Double就像主要的内置类型一样。
double just as the main built-in types.
因此每次创建属性或参数或
So every time you create a property or a parameter or
一个变量，你必须问，是哪一个？
a variable, you have to ask, which one of those?
你得选一个。
You've got to pick one.
如果你做对了，那好吧。
And if you get it right, then okay.
但如果你搞错了程序就会失败
But if you get it wrong, the program is gonna fail and
它不会立即失败必要的。
it's not gonna fail immediately necessary.
事实上，它可能在未来的某一段时间失败，并且测试找不到这一点，
In fact, it might fail some time in the future and tests cannot find that,
因为您的测试都假设有一个特定的数据模型
because your tests all assume a particular data model and
它们不足以查找这些类型的错误。
they are not sufficient for finding these sorts of errors.
测试在这个东西上失败了
Tests fail on this stuff and
选择正确的类型是没有价值的，
there's no value in having picked the right type,
因为我在这个变量上节省了16位。
because I saved 16 bits on this variable.
是的，节省的记忆的现金价值是多少？
Yehey, what's the cash value of the of the savings of that memory?
答案是零。
The answer is zero.
事实上，和你的时间相比根本算不上什么。
In fact, it's nothing compared to your time.
你浪费在决定哪种类型上的时间是无限多的
The time you spent wasted trying to decide which type is infinitely more
比你所节省的记忆的价值更有价值。
valuable than the value of the memory that you're saving.
从另一方面来说，JavaScript做得很好，
Now JavaScript, on the other hand, gets it right,
因为它只有一种数字类型。
because it only has one number type.
这意味着不可能通过选择错误的号码类型和
That means it's impossible to make an error by picking the wrong number type and
这是个巨大的胜利。
that's a huge win.
我完全赞成。
I'm totally in favor of that.
唯一的问题是，它是错误的类型，你知道它是错误的类型，
The only problem is, it's the wrong type and you know it's the wrong type,
因为0.1+0.2不等于0.3。
it's because 0.1+0.2 is not equal to 0.3.
我听过一些人说这无关紧要
I've heard from some people who say that doesn't matter and
他们完全错了，这很重要。
they're absolutely wrong, that matters a lot.
那么，这是怎么发生的？
So, how did this happen?
我们是怎么到这个地方的？
How did we get to this place?
好吧，再一次，我们回到过去。
Well, again, we go back in time.
所以在40年代，当第一台冯·诺依曼机器开始上线时，
So in the 40s, when the first Von Neumann machine start coming online,
它们是只有整数的机器，但大多数程序员都是数学家和
they are integer only machines, but most of the programmers are mathematicians and
他们试图弄清楚如何进行真正的计算，这很难。
they're trying to figure out how to do real computation and it's hard.
他们试图用按比例调整的整数做一些事情，这是一项大量的工作，而且
They're trying to do stuff with scaled integers and it's a lot of work, and
它很容易出错，而且真正聪明的人可以计算出浮点数
it's error prone, and someone who is really smart figures out floating point
我们每个数字都会有两个数字。
that we will have two numbers per number.
一个是数字本身，另一个是比例因子，
One is the number itself and the other is a scale factor,
它告诉我们要移动小数点多少个位置。
which tells us how many positions to move the decimal point.
然后我们可以将其提供给子例程
And then we can just give it to a subroutine and
该子例程将计算出如何添加这些内容，并且它起作用了，并且
the subroutine will figure out how to add these things, and it worked, and
它使编程变得更容易。
it made programming much easier to do.
不幸的是，那些库真的很慢。
Unfortunately, those libraries were really slow.
所以当我们到了50年代，现在有兴趣把浮点放入
So when we get to the 50s, there is now interest in putting floating point into
硬件，但我们正在用管子制造东西，这很难做到。
hardware, but we're making stuff out of tubes and it's hard to do.
一些天才，我相信他是一个天才
And some genius and I do believe he was a genius figured out
如果我们使用二进制浮点而不是十进制浮点，
that if we use binary floating point instead of decimal floating point,
为了进行缩放，我们不必实现除以10。
we don't have to implement a divide by 10 in order to do scaling.
我们可以移动一位，这是免费的。
We can just shift one bit, which is free.
所以，他们就这么做了。
And so, they did that.
现在，这对于科学计算来说非常有效。
Now, that worked great for scientific computing.
因为在科学计算中，
Because in scientific computing,
无论如何，你的低位数字可能是错误的。
your lower order digits are probably wrong, anyway.
因此，不能准确表示十进制数字的事实并不是全部
So the fact that you can't exactly represent the decimal digits is not all
很重要，但它不适用于业务处理，
that important, but it doesn't work for business processing,
因为他们在加钱，他们需要精确。
because they're adding up money and they need to be exact.
他们必须给出准确的感觉。
They have to give the sense exact.
所以有这样的划分，有科学计算和
So there is this division, there is scientific computing and
有商业计算，他们使用不同的硬件。
there is business computing and they use different hardware.
他们使用不同的编程语言。
They use different programming languages.
因此，当您订购大型机时，您要么得到浮点包，要么
So when you order your mainframe, you either get the floating point package or
您将获得用于进行COBOL处理的BCD包。
you get the BCD package for doing your COBOL processing.
这就是世界的运作方式，直到我们进入
And that's sort of the way the world worked until we kind of came into
现代和COBOL消亡了，Java是COBOL的继承者，
the modern age and COBOL dies off and Java is the successor to COBOL,
但是Java来自Fortran学校，而不是COBOL学校。
but Java comes from the Fortran school not from the COBOL school.
它不能很好地处理业务类型，但是
It doesn't do a good job of dealing with the the business types, but
这就是我们现在所处的悲剧。
that's kind of the tragedy that we're in now.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以，我建议修复它，这就是我的解决方案。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So, I propose to fix it and this is my solution.
我调用了DEC64，它是一个64位数量，包含两个
I called DEC64 and it's a 64-bit quantity containing two
数字在很大程度上模仿了他们在40年代所做的事情。
numbers modeled very much after what they were doing in the 40s.
所以我得到了一个数字，它是一个系数。
So I've got one number, which is a coefficient.
它有56位长，我有另一个号码，
It's 56 bits long and I've got another number,
这是指数，它是8位长，并且
which is the exponent, which is 8 bits long and
它真的很好而且很管用，因为这10个。
it's really nice and it works, because of this 10.
所以，真的很容易看到某事将会做什么。
So, it's really easy to see what something is going to do.
只是这个公式，非常简单。
It's just this formula, really really simple.
没有复杂的包装或拆包。
No complicated packing or unpacking.
我把低8位放在底部，因为我是英特尔架构，
I put the lower 8 bits in the bottom, because I'm Intel architecture,
我们可以免费打开它。
we can unpack that for free.
因此软件实现可以非常高效，
So a software implementation can be very efficient and
这让我们得到16或17个小数位，非常准确。
this gets us 16 or 17 decimal places, very accurate.
我们可以做精确的业务处理。
We can do exact business processing.
也不是做科学处理的数据。
It's not data doing scientific processing, either.
所以我的建议是，这是未来应用程序中唯一的数据格式
So my proposal is that this be the only data format in future application
语言，我们只有一种数字类型，就是这一种。
languages, that we just have one number type and it be this one.
为了证明这一点，我有一个可用的软件实现
So to prove it, I have a software implementation available
在DEC64汇编语言中，这是在GitHub上。
in DEC64 assembly language, that's on GitHub.
如果你对此很好奇，你可以去看看，然后
If you're curious about this, you can check it out and and
它表现得很好。
it performs pretty well.
所以如果你在软件实现中添加整数，
So if you're adding integers in a software implementation,
它可以在五个指令中添加两个整数，这是非常好的。
it can add two integers in five instructions, which is pretty good.
可能比你想要的多四个，除了这五个指令
It's maybe four more than you'd like, except that with those five instructions
你也得到了溢出保护和名词，这是很好的东西。
you also get overflow protection and you get nouns, which are nice things to have.
我认为必须拥有的东西。
I think essential things to have.
在硬件实现中，整数相加应该在一个周期内发生，
In a hardware implementation, adding integers should happen in one cycle,
这意味着我们不需要将int作为单独的类型来获得性能。
which means we don't need to have ints as separate type in order to get performance.
我们可以获得性能和
We can get performance and
我们可以在一个数字类型中获得我们需要的值的范围。
we can get the range of values that we need in one number type.
所以，我的目标是让世界上的每个人相信这是唯一的数字类型
So, my goal is to convince everybody in the world that this is the one number type
在下一个系统中使用。
to use in the next system.
现在事实证明，我实际上并不需要说服世界上的每个人。
Now it turns out, I don't actually have to convince everybody in the world.
我只需要说服一个人，就是那个人
I only have to convince one person, that's the man or
设计下一种语言的女人。
the woman who designs the next language.
如果我能说服那个人他们想要一种数字类型的语言
If I can convince that person that they want a language with one number type that
与以我们被教导的方式做算术的人类配合得很好
works well with humans that does arithmetic the way we were taught to do
在学校做算术，这样我们就不会迷惑，然后我们就会赢。
arithmetic in school, so that we won't get confused, then we'll win.